Thornton Chard Correspondence
Thornton Chard Correspondence
1907-1916
Chard, Thornton.
1 linear ft.
Papers of the American architect. Chard's business correspondence (in 10 letter books) with clients.
148896
Biographical History
Thornton Chard was an American architect. Much of his work is in New York City, including the Dave Hennen and Alice Morris House at 19 E. 70th (designated a landmark by the New York City Landmarks Preservation Commission in 1974) and a police station at 156-158 Greenwich Street.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Thornton Chard Papers consist of ten letterbooks containing correspondence of his architectural business from 1907-1916. Contracts mentioned include private homes, churches, and businesses.
Arrangement of the Collection
Letters are arranged chronologically in ten volumes.
Related Material
has the papers of many notable architects. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Architects; Chard, Thornton -- Correspondence.; Architects -- United States.; Architectural practice -- United States.; Correspondence.; Letter books.; Architects.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Volume I, 1907-1909 (Box 1)
  - Volume II, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Volume III, 1909-1910 (Box 1)
  - Volume IV, 1907-1910 (Box 1)
  - Volume V, 1910-1911 (Box 1)
  - Volume VI, 1911 (Box 1)
  - Volume VII, 1911-1912 (Box 1)
  - Volume VIII, 1914 (Box 1)
  - Volume IX, 1915-1916 (Box 1)
  - Volume X, 1916 (Box 1)